Guide to the Lucy Maynard Salmon Historical Materials Collection, 1690-1982 (bulk 1790-1899)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Lucy Maynard Salmon Historical Materials Collection
1690-1982
1790-1899
Salmon, Lucy Maynard, 1853-1927
8 cubic feet (20 boxes); 3 map case folders
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
An artificial collection of letters, diaries, account books, land grants, deeds, wills, and other historical materials originally established by the History Department at Vassar College.
Historical Note
The Vassar College History Department founded the Lucy Maynard Salmon Historical Materials Collection in honor of Lucy Maynard Salmon, a professor in the History Department shortly after her death in 1927. The History Department asked students and alumnae to find historical materials among their families' papers to donate to the collection. Articles were published in The Vassar Quarterly to advertise the creation of the collection and to appeal to students and alumnae for historical items. This collection was proposed as a source for students in Vassar's history classes, as a safe repository for documents, and to increase a "historical sense" among students who donated the documents and objects. This collection was originally proposed as an American history project and excluded all material since 1880, but several documents and objects come from Europe and have been from the period after 1880.
Scope and Content Note
An artificial collection of letters, diaries, account books, land grants, deeds, wills, and other historical materials originally established by the History Department at Vassar College. Includes the Bullard Papers containing letters, charter, petition, bills, receipts, and maps (Dedham, Mass.) relating to the Charles River Meadows Corporation in Massachusetts, 1763-1876; letters of Charles Hawley, 1857-1866, concerning the life of a student at Hamilton College and of a young lawyer in upper New York State; journal of Francis E. Pyle concerning the life of a small shopkeeper in a Pennsylvania village, 1860-1861; typescript copy of the account book of the Rowley family; letters, accounts, and other records of the Williams family of Ithaca, N.Y., 1838-1898; photocopies of letters of Samuel Sawyer, a lawyer of Missouri, 1836-1846; letters of William Galbreath, 1861-1865; and public records of Elizabeth, N.J., 1774-1778.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Separated Materials
The Jasper Parish Papers, originally given to be part of the Salmon Historical Collection, were processed and housed separately.
Subject Headings
Names:
Blanchard, Abbie S.; Blanchard, Clara; Blanchard, Christopher C.; Blanchard, Sally; Blanchard Family; Galbreath, William; Hawley, Charles; Pyle, Francis E.; Rowley family; Sawyer, Samuel; Williams family
Organizations:
Vassar College. Department of History; Charles River Meadows Corporation (Dedham, Mass.); Dean Academy (Franklin, Mass.); Hamilton College (Clinton, N.Y.)--Students
Subjects:
Family--Massachusetts--South Weymouth; Family--New York (State)--Ithaca; High school students--Massachusetts--Franklin; Lawyers--Missouri; Lawyers--New York (State); Real property--Massachusetts--Dedham; Real property--New York (State); Stores, Retail--Pennsylvania; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Women--Diaries; Women--Education
Places:
Dedham (Mass.)--Maps; Elizabeth (N.J.)--Politics and government--18th century; Franklin (Mass.)--Social life and customs--1865-1918; Ithaca (N.Y.)--Social life and customs--19th century; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.)--Politics and government--19th century; South Weymouth (Mass.)--Social life and customs--1865-1918
Document Types:
Account books; Correspondence; Daguerreotypes; Deeds; Diaries; Financial records; Land grants; Maps; Photographs; Property records; Realia; Scrapbooks
VCL Categories:
Education; Family; Local History; Women's History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, August 2008. Last updated by Emma Gronbeck, January 2024.
Acquisition Information
Collection given by Vassar College History Department and various donors in honor of Lucy Maynard Salmon.
Series List
- Series I. Atwater Photographs and Daguerreotypes, 1840 - circa 1954
- Series II. Blanchard Family Papers, 1879
  Historical Note
  Abbie S. Blanchard and her sisters, Alice and Clara, were the daughters of Christopher C. Blanchard and his wife, Sally. The family lived in South Weymouth, Massachusetts, in the second half of the nineteenth century. Mr. Blanchard conducted a boot and shoe business, W.and C. Blanchard, in Massachusetts and New Orleans. Abbie and Clara attended Dean Academy in Franklin, Massachusetts.
  Scope and Content Note
  This series consists of a diary kept by Abbie S. Blanchard while attending Dean Academy in Franklin, Massachussetts, along with her sister Clara. The diary discusses Blanchard's dissatisfaction with school rules, etiquette lectures, social life with other students, visits home, dancing lesson, and young men. Also includes other miscellaneous family papers.
  Acquisition Information
  Donated to the Lucy Maynard Salmon Collection of Historical Materials, Vassar College Library, by Mary Louise Hukill (VC 1945-4).
- Series III. Bleecker Family Papers, 1695-1813
- Series IV. Bullard Family Papers, 1766-1869
- Series V. Civil War Materials, 1861-1865
- Series VI. Cook Family Papers, 1850-1885
- Series VII. Hallock Family Letters, circa 1836 - 1905
- Series VIII. Henking Papers, undated
- Series IX. Hoge Papers, 1788-1825
- Series X. Lee Papers, 1838-1863
- Series XI. Miller Papers, 1880, undated
- Series XII. Scottish Immigrant Family, 1851-1864
- Series XIII. Williams Family Papers, 1848-1898
- Series XIV. Poughkeepsie Materials, 1871-1922
- Series XV. Correspondence, 1799-1948
- Series XVI. Notebooks, Diaries, Journals, Scrapbooks, and Account Books, 1732-1982
- Series XVII. Land Documents and Deeds, 1598-1864
- Series XVIII. Government Materials, 1547-1898
- Series XIX. Wills, Legal Documents and Business Papers, 1662-1868
- Series XX. Miscellaneous Items and Realia, 1754-1969
Container List
- SERIES I. Atwater Photographs and Daguerreotypes
  - List of photos and daguerreotypes (Folder 4.1)
  - Photographs — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 4.2)
  - Photographs — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 4.2)
  - Photographs — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 4.2)
  - Photographs — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 4.2)
  - Photographs — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, 1880s? (Folder 4.2)
  - Photographs — Evelyn Atwater Cummins, 1894 (Folder 4.3)
  - Photographs — Empress Eugenie (?) (Folder 4.4)
  - Photographs — Queen Victoria (Folder 4.4)
  - Photographs — Jennie Lind and Goldsmith (Folder 4.4)
  - Photographs — Jessie Fremont (Folder 4.4)
  - Photographs — William Cullen Bryant (Folder 4.4)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, age 10, 1863 (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, standing, undated (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, seated, undated (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, when a student at Andover, 1870; (2 copies) (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, sophomore at Yale, 1873?; (2 copies) (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, senior at Yale, 1875; (2 copies) (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — Edward Storrs Atwater, just before his marriage, Apr 1879; (2 copies) (Folder 4.5)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater daguerreotype, 1840 (Folder 4.6)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater, March 1863; (2 copies) (Folder 4.6)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 4.6)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater, 1871 (Folder 4.6)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater, 1886 (Folder 4.6)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater, circa 1890s (Folder 4.6)
  - Photographs — John Phelps Atwater, Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, and Edward Storrs Atwater in frame, circa 1856? (Folder 4.7)
  - Photographs — Branch (Folder 4.8)
  - Photographs — Alphonso Taft (Folder 4.9)
  - Photographs — Fanny Phelps Taft from an earlier daguerreotype (Folder 4.10)
  - Photographs — Evelyn A. Cummins' notes on the subjects of the pictures (Folder 4.11)
  - Daguerreotypes — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, age 17 before her marriage, 1845 (Folder 5.1)
  - Daguerreotypes — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 5.2)
  - Daguerreotypes — Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater with her son, Edward Storrs Atwater, circa 1954 (Folder 5.3)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, Lucy Jane Phelps Atwater, Ethan Stone, circa 1851 (Folder 5.4)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, circa 1840s (Folder 5.5)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, circa 1840 (Folder 5.6)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, circa 1855 (Folder 5.7)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 5.8)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, undated (Folder 5.9)
  - Daguerreotypes — John Phelps Atwater, circa 1954 (Folder 5.10)
  - Daguerreotypes — Edward Storrs Atwater, undated (Folder 5.11)
  - Daguerreotypes — Fanny Phelps Taft, undated (Folder 5.12)
  - Daguerreotypes — Frances Swift, Elma Swift, Caroline Swift (Atwater), Charles W. Swift, 2nd, undated (Folder 5.13)
  - Envelopes from Atwater photographs and daguerreotypes (Box 6)
- SERIES II. Blanchard Family Papers
  - Abbie S. Blanchard Diary, 1879 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
- SERIES III. Bleeker Papers, Albany, NY, 1695-1813
  - Account (1) "Our chgs. Oct. 20 Lucas 995,", undated (Box 1)
  - Account (2) "Dr. Jacob Bleecker Jr. with Beeckman and Ten Eyck,", 10 July 1788? (Box 1)
  - Account (3) Interest, 1790 (Box 1)
  - Account (4) Interest, 1791-1794 (Box 1)
  - Account (5) Interest — William Foster's (?) Interest account, 30 May 1793-23 June 1795 (Box 1)
  - Account (6) Butcher?, 6 Nov1801-31 Dec 1802 (Box 1)
  - "Advertisement" concerning patriotism, undated (Box 1)
  - Assessment List (?), 11 Jan 1732/1733 (Box 1)
  - Bill of Sale, 20 March 1792 (Box 1)
  - Bleecker, Harmanus — Portrait, undated (Box 1)
  - Deed, 9 n.m. 1770 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 1772 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 15 June 1772 (Box 1)
  - Deed – registered 6 July 1772 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 23 Dec 1775 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 7 Dec 1784 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 3 June 1790 (Box 1)
  - Deed, Aug 1792? (Box 1)
  - Document on Indian Affairs, (fragment) (Box 1)
  - Invoices, etc., 1773 (or earlier?)-1806; (22) (Box 1)
  - [Concerning] lands, 5 Jan 1739 (Box 1)
  - Lease, 11 Feb 1791 (Box 1)
  - Letter — addressed "Sir" "I am informed that you are riding away my logs…" unsigned, 28 Feb 1789; (AL) (Box 1)
  - Letter — addressed "Sir" signed "JBJ (Jr.?)", 23 Sep 1790; (ALS) (Box 1)
  - Marriage License, 27 May 1796 (Box 1)
  - Memoranda, 23 Aug 1774, undated (Box 1)
  - Military List, undated (Box 1)
  - Note, undated, 7 June 1803; (ALS) (Box 1)
  - Promissory Note, 16 June 1772 (Box 1)
  - Promissory Notes, 30 Oct 1784, 18 Apr 1797, 1 Nov 1813; (3 items) (Box 1)
  - Promissory Note, 25 Apr 1789 (Box 1)
  - Promissory Note, 1 Oct 1795 (Box 1)
  - Receipts, 1772-1806; (14 items) (Box 1)
  - Statement, 19 Feb 1778 (Box 1)
  - Statement (concerning house in Albany), 1741 (Box 1)
  - Deed, undated (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Deed, 23 Oct 1695 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Deed, 27 Oct 1695 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Deed, 8 Oct 1787 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Lease, 28 July 1789 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Deed, 29 July 1789 (Box 17 (Oversize))
- SERIES IV. Bullard Family Papers
  - Account book, 1814-1826 (Folder 3.1)
  - County papers and orders, 1768-1835, undated (Folder 3.1)
  - County papers and orders, 1767-1809, undated (Folder 3.2)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1786-1869, undated (Folder 3.3)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1798-1807, undated (Folder 3.4)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1827-1841, undated (Folder 3.5)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1790-1804, undated (Folder 3.6)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1795-1810, undated (Folder 3.7)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1792-1811, undated (Folder 3.8)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1820-1845, undated (Folder 3.9)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1799-1851, undated (Folder 3.10)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1824-1829, undated (Folder 3.11)
  - Old papers pertaining to the County of Norfolk, 1784-1809, undated (Folder 3.12)
  - Bills A-E of Bullard Family, 1809-1829, undated (Folder 3.13)
  - Bills F-Z of Bullard Family, 1786-1804, undated (Folder 3.14)
  - Certificate of Fines with fees paid by Justice of the Peace, 1850-1851, undated (Folder 3.15)
  - Bills F-Z of Bullard Family, 1809-1829 (Folder 3.16)
  - Payments received by Bullard Family, 1794-1805 (Folder 3.17)
  - Payments received by Bullard family, 1795-1796, undated (Folder 3.18)
  - Bills and received payment notices Bullard Family, 1816-1837 (Folder 3.19)
  - Debts owed to Bullard family, 1790-1807 (Folder 3.20)
  - Bills paid toward the town lands, 1829-1830 (Folder 3.21)
  - Accounts settled, 1790-1808 (Folder 3.22)
  - Accounts settled, 1773-1807 (Folder 3.23)
  - Church accounts, accounts settled, 1796-1808 (Folder 3.24)
  - Plan of Dedham Village (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of map of Dedham, 18 June 1794 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of document about Meadow land upon Charles River (part of Bullard papers?), 15 Sep 1766 (Box 18 (Oversize))
- SERIES V. Civil War Materials
  - Confederate States Documents, (10 pieces) (Box 1)
  - Confederate Notes (Box 1)
  - Message Book — Headquarters of the Confederate Army, Dept of Western Virginia and East Tennessee, 1864 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Number of pages from Civil War diary, 1863-1864; [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - William Erving Champlain to family, 1862; (3 letters, 3 typescripts, obituary) (Box 19)
  - William Galbraith to Mother, 22 July 1861 (Box 19)
  - Robert ? to Mother, 1 May 1865 (Box 19)
  - C.S. Jenkins to Ned, 2 July 1864; (Photostat, typescript) (Box 19)
  - Edward L. Parker to Brigadier General S.R. Gist, 9 Apr 1862; (Photostat, typescript) (Box 19)
  - Lewis B. Parsons to Thomas Lough Esquire, 2 Feb [186?]; (typescript only) (Box 19)
  - Richard C. Pope to Madam, 6 Sep 1864; (typescript, Photostat) (Box 19)
  - Letter Book — Headquarters of the Confederate Army, Dept of Western Virginia and East Tennessee, undated (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Lincoln, civil war material including pins, civil war songs, campaign ribbon, funeral badge, cartoons, buttons, portraits, medal (Box 12)
  - E.B. Bigelow-Company "B" 5th Michigan Regiment list, undated (Box 19)
- SERIES VI. Cook Family Papers
  - Account Book (American) from Cook Family Papers (Box 1)
  - Georgie Cook to Carrie Cook, 26 June 1885 (Box 19)
  - W.F. Jones to William Cook, 19 Oct 1857 (Box 19)
  - M. Montgomery to Mr. Bissell, 15 June 1850 (Box 19)
  - Dr. M.J. Moore to Mrs. Cook, undated (Box 19)
- SERIES VII. Hallock Family Letters
  - Hannah Conant Letters, 1851, 1885, 1894; (3 letters) (Box 19)
  - Martha Hallock Falconer to Elizabeth Foote, 25 Apr 1881 (Box 19)
  - Annie Jean Bailey Fletcher correspondence, 1863, 1869-1872 (Box 19)
  - Warren Fletcher to Elizabeth Foote, 1867, 1872; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Elizabeth L. Foote to niece Lizzie, 1905; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Elizabeth Hallock-obituary and letter about her death, undated (Box 19)
  - Samuel T. Hallock correspondence, 1872, 1880; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Sarah Crosby Bailey Hallock correspondence, 1838, 1851, 1881; (3 letters) (Box 19)
  - Mary Bailey Peterson to Sarah C.B. Hallock, 4 Dec 1858 (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook and account book of Samuel T. Hallock and family, circa 1836 (Box 15 (Oversize))
- SERIES VIII. Henking Papers
  - Henking Papers - 1 (Box 1)
  - Henking Papers - 2 (Box 1)
  - Henking Papers - 3 (Box 1)
- SERIES IX. Hoge Papers
  - Photostat of Letter of General Lafayette to Colonel Paul Bentadon, 27 Apr 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Letter of L.H. Girandin to Maximilian Godfrey Esquire, 30 Jan 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to Colonel Paul Bentadon, 21 March 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to unknown, 12 March 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to unknown, 7 March 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to unknown, 1 July 1812 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to unknown, 31 Dec 1822 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to unknown, 23 May 1818 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of James Monroe to unknown, 16 July 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of note and envelope addressed to the Comte de Rochenbeau, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of Guibeuf? to unknown, 1788 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of Guibeuf?, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of Guibeuf? To unknown, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
- SERIES X. Lee Papers
  - Civil War — Draft form, checks, 1863 (Box 1)
  - Civil War Document — Draft form, 1863 (Box 1)
  - Charters — Old Colony Account, Sheet from Account Book, note, 1840 (Box 1)
  - Passport (Lee papers), 1843 (Box 2)
  - S. Austin Jr. to Henry Lee Jr., 11 Sep 1838 (Box 19)
  - Brian and Humphreys to Henry Lee Jr., 31 Oct 1838 (Box 19)
  - Henry Hall to Henry Lee Jr., 10 Sep 1838 (Box 19)
  - C. Higginson to Henry Lee Jr., 28 Sep 1838 (Box 19)
  - Henry Lee Letters, Sep-Oct 1838; (6 letters) (Box 19)
  - Henry Lee Jr. Letter, 11 Sep 1838 (Box 19)
  - Miller, LeCocq and Co. to Henry Lee Jr., 1839-1840; (3 letters) (Box 19)
  - Robert G. Shaw and Co. to Henry Lee Jr., 8 Sep 1838 (Box 19)
  - C. Stetson to Henry Lee Jr., 29 May 1839 (Box 19)
  - T.W. Ward to Henry Lee Jr., 5 Oct 1838 (Box 19)
- SERIES XI. Miller Papers
  - Correspondence of Charles Benjamin Miller, Jefferson Davis, Thomas Porter Miller (Box 10)
  - Confederate money (Box 10)
  - Letter book of Mercy Miller (Box 10)
  - Prescription (Box 10)
  - J.R. Abrams letters, 1880; (3 letters) (Box 19)
- SERIES XII. Scottish Immigrant Family
  - Thomas H. Clark to Mrs. Sarah Galbraith, 4 July 1862 (Box 19)
  - Elizabeth Gillies to sister; to Thomas Galbraith, 1851, 1859, 1864; (3 letters) (Box 19)
  - James McDivet to sister, 1851; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Robert McGowan to Sarah Gillies Galbraith, 1862 (Box 19)
  - Mary Robison to Mrs. Waddle, 15 Oct 1860 (Box 19)
  - Margaret Stewart to sister and note, 1860, 1864; (2 letters) (Box 19)
- SERIES XIII. Williams Family Papers
  - Genealogy of Williams Family, undated (Box 19)
  - Humphrey Bell to parents, 16 June 1852 (Box 19)
  - E.A. Ingersoll to Cynthia Whiton, 1855-1857; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - J.W. Ingersoll to Cynthia Whiton?, 1861, 1871, 1877; (3 letters) (Box 19)
  - Mary Ingersoll to Cynthia Whiton, 1848-1857, 1870-1872, undated; (12 letters) (Box 19)
  - Emanuel Russell to Mrs. Charity Williams, 2 June 1860 (Box 19)
  - Cynthia Whiton to Mother, cousins, 1855; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Charity Williams letter, 12 Sep 1898 (Box 19)
  - T.S. Williams to parents, 22 Nov 1838 (Box 19)
- SERIES XIV. Poughkeepsie Materials
  - Whaling Companies Poughkeepsie (Box 2)
  - Poughkeepsie City and Wappingers Falls Electric Railway Company Bond, signed by James William Hinkley President, biography and other information included (Box 8)
  - Second Bounty Loan, signed by E. White, mayor, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1884 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Water Loan $1000 4 per cent, signed by Charles Auden, mayor, Poughkeepsie, NY, 2 March 1896 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Certificate of Indebtness, signed by Isaac Sherrill, mayor, Poughkeepsie, NY, 25 May 1900 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Letter to Isaac Sherrill when he was City Chamberlain, Poughkeepsie, NY, 2 May 1885 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - $1000 7 per cent Water Stock, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1 May 1871 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - City loan $700 6 per cent signed by George Innis, mayor, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1 March 1865 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Sale of $700 City Loan, Poughkeepsie, NY, 8 Sep 1876 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Sewerage Debt $1000 7 per cent, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1 Feb 1873 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Transfer of sewerage debts #33, 24, 35, 36, 37, Poughkeepsie, NY, 26 Feb 1884 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Sewerage Debt $1000 7 per cent, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1 Aug 1872 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - $1000 Water Loan 3 ½ per cent, signed by J. Frankhurt, mayor, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1 May 1897 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - $1000 Water Loan 3 ½ per cent, signed by N.M. Ketcham, mayor, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1 May 1893 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - City of Poughkeepsie Bonded Debt, 1 March 1901 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - City of Poughkeepsie Certificate appointing Inspectors of roads in Dutchess County, 17 Apr 1830 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Poughkeepsie lease, signed by [Rose Mills?], 1 May 1922 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- SERIES XV. Correspondence
  - Friends, Society of – Devonshire Meeting, 5 Apr 1803 (Box 1)
  - Mexico Revolution — copy of part of a letter sent by Miss V. Gurney from a Mexican civil engineer of high social position, July 1915 (Box 2)
  - Letters — Griggs, Emily M. (VC Faculty 1866/1867-music teacher), 9 Feb 1864-9 July 1869; (19 letters) (Box 2)
  - Letters — Reynolds Family, 1864, 1882; (6 letters) (Box 2)
  - Whiting Papers (Box 2)
  - Whitley, Sir Edward, M.P. — letters to Lewis Dennison Bement, 10 Dec 1952-22 Aug 1963; (36 letters) (Box 2)
  - One folder with miscellaneous correspondence, newspaper clippings, ledger pages (Box 8)
  - List of letters given by Theodora M. Carrell (Box 8)
  - Letter — Eliza Campten to Mrs. Medford, 21 Jan 1830 (Folder 11.4)
  - Letter — Joseph Blunt to Mrs. Hynson, 1836 (Folder 11.5)
  - Letter — unknown, 21 July 1873 (Folder 11.6)
  - Le Bomirer - letter, 25 Apr 1898 (Folder 11.16)
  - Letter — Robert Galbraith to mother, 21 Jan 1863 (Folder 11.17)
  - Letter to mother, undated (Folder 11.18)
  - Letter — Mrs. Frederick J. Fist to Annie, undated (Folder 11.18)
  - Letter to Emily Ogden, 19 Jan 1834 (Folder 11.20)
  - Folding file with miscellaneous letters, newspaper clippings (Box 11)
  - Letters from Europe, 1865-1866 by Amy Grinell Smith and Mary Ermina Smith, edited by David Sanders Clark, 1948 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter to "Sir" from G. Washenphor, 27 Oct 1799 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Letter of Amos Steele to his uncle, 1 March 1866 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Letter to Caroline Arnold, 9 Jan 1845 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Letter of Levi Arnold to Benjamin Arnold, 17 May 1808 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Letter of Levi Arnold to Benjamin Arnold, 10May 1808 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostats of Calk Papers (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Matted photograph and letter of unknown subject and autograph (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Letters of A. L. Ballard, 1837-1838 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Letter of Dan Williams, 1836 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter of John Quincy Adams, 1837 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Letters of Samuel Sawyer and Henry Callaway of Elm Forest and Lexington, MO, 1846, 1849 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Letter unknown to Bill, relating to secession, 4 March 1861 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Letter of John Brown, written during his imprisonment, 1859; (facsimile) (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Charles J. Baldwin letters, 1872; (typescripts only) (Box 19)
  - Letter of Widow Ballantine from Gibraltar, 1805 (Box 19)
  - C.P. Benton to Sophronie Baldwin, 9 June 1840; (Photostat, typescript) (Box 19)
  - William Berrian to Major Lawrence Lewis, 29 July 1819 (Box 19)
  - Charles H. Berry to C.N. Waterman, 1852; (typescript) (Box 19)
  - Charles H. Berry to Kate Berry, 1874-1875; (8 letters) (Box 19)
  - Mrs. Charles H. Berry to Darling Kate, undated; (2 letters) (Box 19)